Shopee | Regional Salesforce Business Analyst

Address

374 Laurel Wood Avenue, 275970, Singapore

Contac

matthew.auw@gmail.com +6583222704

PROFILE

A business analyst with experience in the fields of management and technology consulting. In my time in the consulting industry, I have had the opportunity to deliver best practice solutions to some of the largest government clients in Singapore. I am now utilising my expertise to lead regional business development initiatives in countries across the APAC region and drive innovation through the adoption of Salesforce.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Shopee Singapore Oct 2020 – Current

Business Analyst | Regional Salesforce Business Process Reengineering – Business Development Process Design / Implementation

- Regional Salesforce business analyst for Southeast Asia
- Worked collaboratively with local teams and SF developers to analyse country business requirements and identify key processes for onboarding to Salesforce
- Developed the project strategy and executed full-cycle implementation from requirements gathering to business process reengineering and user training
- Analysed regional KPIs to derive key trends and liaised with local and regional PICs in coordinating monthly target setting and quarterly incentive pay-outs

Citibank Singapore

Mar 2020 - Oct 2020 Business Analyst | Regional Business Transformation

Strategy and Business Transformation

 Partnered with regional and local teams across the APAC and EMEA regions to successfully execute regional strategic initiatives for the Global Consumer Bank relating to performance growth and COVID-19 WFH enablement & productivity

Accenture Singapore

Feb 2018 - Mar 2020 Consulting Analyst | Health & Public Service Business Process Reengineering - Finance Transformation / Shared Services Design

- Partnered with multiple large government agencies in the streamlining of business processes across the Finance function
- Reengineered and delivered >200 Finance processes across 9 pillars of Finance, involving >80 workshops conducted with >1000 participants combined

Workday Finance Implementation

• Delivered business process design sessions and gathered functional requirements for the configuration of Workday Finance modules (AP, Asset Management)

Technology Modernisation

• Analysed >10 programs with >20,000 lines of code for system redesign

Citco Fund Services

Apr 2017 - Feb 2018 Operations Analyst

Hedge Fund Administration

 Oversaw and managed fund administration activities for various client hedge funds with a combined AUM of USD\$2B

EDUCATION

The University of Western Australia | 2016 - 2016

Bachelor of Commerce (Honours in Finance)

 Thesis: "Firm Performance and Financial Decisions of State-Owned Firms During Financial Crises: Evidence from China"

The University of Western Australia | 2013 – 2015

Bachelor of Commerce – Double major in Accounting and Finance

- GPA: High Distinction (6.54/7)
- Academic Achievement Award Recipient

Overseas Family School | 2007 - 2010

Diploma of the International Baccalaureate

SKILLS

- Business strategy
- Management consulting
- Technology consulting
- Project management
- Business process design
- Business process reengineering
- Shared services design
- Design Thinking
- PowerPoint and presentation skills

CERTIFICATES

Certified Workday Consultant | Feb 2019 - Current

 Certified to design, solution, and implement Workday Finance modules